The truth is sometimes a hard pill to
swallow. It sometimes causes us
difficulties at home and abroad.
And the CIA literally in in the span of
a day transformed from an organization
whose mission was to recruit spies to
steal secrets
to a paramilitary organization.
When the values that define our nation
are intentionally disregarded by our
security policies, even those policies
that are conducted in secret.
>> If Russia had joined NATO, do you think
we'd be in the same mess we're in now?
>> No.
>> And that pendulum has not swung back
yet.
I I'm not sure that it will. He was
going to pardon me and Assange and
Snowden.
But then,
[Music]
all right, we're joined today by John
Kiryaku. How are you doing today, John?
>> Very well, thanks. How are you?
>> I'm doing well and I'm really glad to
get a chance to meet you. I've
interviewed different CIA officers and
yes, I've learned it's officers, not
agents. That's right. And um it's a pet
peeve of ours.
>> Oh yeah, that that's been made clear.
Even though I also interviewed um an
SACE from the FBI and he made it clear
that you never call them a sack.
>> That's funny.
>> So they have their own pet peeves, too.
>> It's like why? Well, you don't want to
be called a sack. Why? What could that
mean? But um you um were in the CIA for
a while near a whistleblower and I know
you've probably repeated it 5,000 times,
but can you give a thumbnail sketch
about what happened that made you decide
you maybe you quit in 2004
and then I believe you did an interview
in 2007, but you didn't get any trouble
about that.
>> Oh, I got lots of trouble.
>> Okay. I got yeah I I gave an interview
to ABC News in 2007 in which I said that
the CIA was torturing its prisoners,
that torture was official US government
policy and that the policy had been
personally approved by the president.
The white the the CIA within 24 hours of
that interview uh reported me to the FBI
saying that I had revealed not just
classified information to the media but
top secret information in the media. The
FBI investigated me for a year from
December of 2007 until December of 2008.
But they determined that I had not
committed a crime because it is illegal
to classify a criminal act for the
purpose of keeping the information from
the American people. And so they
declined to prosecute me. Three weeks
later, Barack Obama becomes president
and he names John Brennan as the uh
deputy national security adviser for
counterterrorism. John asked Eric
Holder, the new attorney general, to
secretly reopen the case against me.
They investigated me for three more
years and then in January of 2012
charged me with five felonies, including
three counts of espionage coming out of
that ABC News interview. This, however,
was not a case about leaking. This was a
case about torture. And I believe I'm
going to prison because I blew the
whistle on torture. I've been a thorn in
the CIA's side since that interview in
2007 in which I said that waterboarding
was torture and that it was official US
government policy. And I think finally
the Justice Department caught up with
me. So this would be John Brennan um
communist John Brennan literally who
voted for the Communist
uh party of America I believe twice.
Yeah. He uh and he treated it as a big
joke like like the the franchise is is
worthy of just throwing it away by
making a joke and voting for Gus Hall,
the Communist Party USA nominee for
president.
>> Okay. So, I I just wanted to throw that
out there because
>> Yeah, you're absolutely right.
>> Always been disturbed. Um I am
admittedly not a fan of Brennan. I'm not
a fan of Clapper.
>> Um
Clapper, I feel committed perjury in
front of Congress.
>> Most most clearly. Yes.
>> And has never apologized.
>> No. And I you know that's funny because
people have gone to prison for contempt
of Congress, I believe, and for perjury.
So, it's very confusing.
>> Those are two those are two crimes that
that Democrats made great use of in the
first Trump administration. They sent a
lot of people to the dock for contempt
of Congress and for perjury.
Yeah. But but you're right, Brennan and
Clapper never went to prison for for
either of those crimes. Now, one thing,
maybe you can help me clear it up
because there does seem to be a bit of a
discrepancy. Uh if I recall, Obama was
one of the only senators who voted
against the Iraq war.
He
>> Okay.
>> He voted
>> he was elected to the Senate after the
Iraq war uh had begun.
>> Okay.
>> But he voted repeatedly to fund the Iraq
war.
>> I see. So he ran being against it. Yeah.
>> But then he voted for it.
>> Correct.
>> And then he peed on the same people.
>> Um like Gates, I believe, you know, when
he came over. So he was all for the Iraq
war then in the end.
>> Mhm. He was sure
>> you know
>> John Kerry who you worked for who threw
his medals during Vietnam.
>> Well there's a story there.
>> Oh please tell me
in in
December of 2008. Carrie called me and
said that well we we had a mutual friend
and he said that he was going to become
the chairman of the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee. he was going to
reconstitute the committee's um
investigative function and would I be
interested in taking a job as the senior
investigator on the on the foreign
relations committee. I said I'd be
interested in the conversation. I went
up to his office to speak to him. So I
go into the office. It was in the
Russell Senate office building, which is
the original Senate Office Building.
It's very historic, high ceilings.
That's where everybody wants to be. You
go into Car's office at the time and
literally from the floor to the 15 foot
ceiling of the room, there are framed
pictures of Carrie with every world
leader you can imagine. From Gorbachav
to the Pope to the Daly Lama and
everybody in between. It's kind of cool,
but it's sort of an altar to himself.
When you first walk in, there's a
credenza on the left. And the credenza
had three things on it. it on the left
was a picture of Carrie in an embrace
with John Lennon and they're like giving
each other nookies. Very cool picture.
Who wouldn't want to have his picture
joking around with John Lennon like
that? On the other side of the credenza
was a a picture of Carrie with Peter
Paul and Mary the folk group. He was
friendly with all of them. He gave the
eulogy at Mary Travers funeral. Very
close. In the middle was a shadow box
with his medals in it.
And when the meeting ended, I went out.
I left the office and uh and the chief
of staff said, "Well, how did it go?"
And I said, "Oh, it was great. He
offered me the job. I told him I'd take
it, but I got a question." I said, "The
shadow box with the medals." I said,
"What's up with that?" He threw the
medals over the White House. Everybody
in America knew that he had thrown the
medals over the White House fence to
protest the Vietnam War.
and he laughed and he said, "Those
medals are the most important things in
his life." That morning he went to the
PX and bought copies of the medals and
threw the copies over the White House
fence.
I said, "So it's all these years,
decades,
it was all based on a lie.
That's John Ky. That's the real John Ky.
That's a perfect character statement
rolled up in the thumbnail, which is
really damning
>> in my opinion. It It reminds me of
Lyndon Baines Johnson and his Silver
Star.
>> Oh boy, we could tell stories about
Johnson for the next hour.
>> Well, actually, I have. I have another
show called America's Untold Stories. My
partner has dug deep into that and um
yes, there's loads about LBJ
similar.
>> You've heard the story about LBJ's first
congressional race 1946. He was an
internal poll show or 40
>> six or 48.
>> Well, there was Fox 13 if that's where
you're going.
>> No, it was the uh an internal poll
showed him showed him uh trailing uh his
opponent and he told the campaign
manager, "Let's let's start a rumor that
he had sex with a pig." And and the the
uh campaign manager said, "But he hasn't
had sex with a pig." And Johnson said,
"I know he hasn't, but let's make the
son of a [__] deny it." And he ended up
winning the race.
>> Well, he did. Okay. And then more
famously later on, he became Lanclide
Lynon with the box 13 and running the
Mexicans, which by the way, uh, in odd
fairness to him, he got burned the
election before that. So, he learned,
oh, we've got to make sure to keep
counting the votes until they square up
for us. Always have a few out there. So,
>> and I think that one's been pretty well
proven.
>> Yeah.
>> But yeah. Okay. So, um you've been in
the thick of all the shenanigans. I've
been just kind of on the side reading
and researching and things like that,
but I wanted to share um an interview
that I did three years ago with a
another CIA officer and I believe you've
debated him. I haven't seen the full
debate. I just know that you debated
him. Andrew Bamanti. Mhm.
>> And I kind of had a little disagreement
with him. And you may completely agree
with him, you may agree with me, but I
wanted to see if I could just play the
clip and and see what you think because
I think it may
represent some views inside the CIA.
>> And once you make something subjective,
now all of a sudden you make it a battle
of wills and morals. Wills and morals
should not exist in the world of
national security.
>> Right? Again, who are you protecting?
The citizens, right?
>> Okay.
>> I mean, the country is made up by
citizens. Technically, everybody in the
government works for the people. The
citizens, the people,
>> that's not that's actually not true. The
people in government do not work for the
citizens. Citizens can't vote on their
government employees.
>> That gets into a deep state, but that's
bureaucratic element of it that they
can't vote on it, but they can't vote on
who's appointing the people and who is
running the agency. So technically we're
on steps that are removed but ultimately
the government is supposedly working for
the taxpayer
>> and we get into the details of the deep
state and the bureaucratical element of
it and
>> none of that has to do with the deep
state man. None of that has to do with
the deep
>> well deep state is just another term for
a bureaucracy just for the people who
have been there for 20 years and they're
there through every politician coming
and going. It's just it sounds really
creepy. So, I'm not I'm not saying deep
state in that sense, but um
>> now I may have been meandering a bit
there. Um and what I probably forgot to
express is that I I was a soldier at one
point. I didn't, you know, go around
like Pete Turner or whatever, but I
swore an oath to the Constitution as a
soldier.
>> Absolutely.
>> And that oath to the Constitution I in
my personal view is a an oath to the
American people ultimately.
>> You swore to uphold the Constitution and
to protect it against all enemies,
domestic and foreign. It's the same oath
that I took. And Andrew Bamante is
wrong, wrong, wrong in that position. He
used that same position in the debate
that I had with him on the Danny Jones
podcast. And the thing about Andrew,
he's very, very bright, but he puts
himself into into a a a
box or a corner that he can't get out
of. He's just wrong in that position. We
are public employees. We answer to the
American people and you know when you
enter the federal bureaucracy and like
you the I I believe that the federal
bureaucracy is the deep state. You can
call it the state, you can call it the
bureaucracy, you can call it the deep
state. It's all the same thing. But we
are a a nation of laws and we are a
nation that has a living and breathing
constitution that we have to defend and
protect. And we cannot and should not
violate the law
and pretend as Andrew says that we don't
have any moral component to the work
that we do. Of course we do.
We're not authoritarians.
Well, and that's what I wanted to
express because I I, you know, talked to
different people and I've watched it and
I've debated around and I haven't
changed my mind on it. It's kind of a I
I feel like that was a an important
moment that I fear, I could be wrong,
um, illustrates the culture that I think
may be within the CIA or maybe was
within the CIA. Is that fair? Yes, that
was the culture in the CIA
beginning on 911
and going all the way
well, I'm going to say even even today,
it's it's still a part of the culture
because we've got organizations like the
Special Activities Division or Global
Resources uh uh group or special
activities group in counterterrorism
whose job it is to fly around the world
and kill people.
So, yes, everything changed on 911.
>> Now, while everything is changing
because I' I've done a lot of stuff with
the CIA. You got MK Ultra. You got other
things where the CIA's hands haven't
always been clean or they maybe never
been clean. I don't know. And I
understand that it's kind of a dirty
business. So there may have to be issues
going here and there, but
it seems like the CIA has in fact done a
bit of drug running.
>> I've interviewed um DEA people. I don't
know if you've ever seen this show
Narcos.
>> Oh, loved it. Never missed an episode.
>> Uh I interviewed both Javier and
>> Oh, great.
>> Um and Steve, um his name slipp my mind.
I interviewed both of them and one thing
Javier especially said is there was
nobody more hated by the DEA than the
CIA.
>> CIA because those scenes in Narcos where
the DEA is right on the brink of of
getting you know the big guy whether
it's Pablo Escobar or the gentleman of
Cali or whomever and the CIA steps in
just screws the pooch
that was in Narcos because that's what
really happened.
The CIA doesn't give a [__] about drugs.
The CIA at the time cared about
communism. Drugs were somebody else's
problem. DEA, maybe FBI, but communism
is all that the CIA cared about at the
time.
>> Well, that was kind of his founding um
doctrine, right? That's right.
>> That's cold.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And um I and I'll also say that he
personally held a grudge because of Kiki
Kamarana. Mhm.
>> Uh who
>> and and he had every rightly.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. So there there are real questions
about the CIA involvement in the death
of Kiki Kamarana.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> I I don't know the inside story, but
I've heard the same rumors that you
have.
>> Wasn't until you a year later that I
recruit the third guy that was there,
Ramol, who who we all know about now.
And I brought him in and I said, "Okay,
tell me who interrogated Kiki." And he
starts running me to everybody that
interrogated Kiki and how they tortured
him and everything else. And then he
says, "And there was a Cuban guy
that
interrogated Kiki and his name was
Ismael Phelis Rodriguez."
I says, "Who's he?" He's a CIA
operative. He interrogated Kiki.
>> Okay. Well, I've also interviewed um
another DEA agent um Mike Lavine, and he
talked about
a a DIA
operative who
was arrested
ultimately and then he died and they
sensed cyanide on him when they first
did the necropsy or whatever.
>> And then later on they said, "Oh, no,
no, no, no. It was it was an allergy, a
a a peanut butter allergy because he he
died of a peanut butter sandwich. And
and the where I'm going with this is he
was on Phil Donahue with um
uh another individual, Gary Webb, I
think you might have heard of.
>> Yeah, I was the uh script adviser on the
film uh Kill the Messenger about Gary
Webb.
>> Oh, wow. Okay. Well, Mike Lavine was on
Phil Donghue with Gary Webb and
apparently he got a phone call in the
green room right before going on and um
they essentially sold him be careful
or you may have a peanut butter sandwich
and
that was some dark and scary thing. So I
I guess where I'm going is that did the
CIA because you kind of over overlapped.
You were in the CIA for uh 11 years
before 911.
>> Almost. Yeah. 11 years before 911.
That's right. Yeah.
>> So the majority of your CIA career could
actually be seen as pre 911.
>> Yes.
>> Was it changing?
>> Oh,
there there were real eras
that we can we can point to with
definitive
beginnings and ends. Um
I I entered the CIA at the tail end of
the cold war where we were talking about
the peace dividend. We started liazing
with Warsaw packed countries and you
know exchanging intelligence. We're
talking about the Russians maybe joining
NATO back then and everybody was all,
you know, milk and honey.
And then
and then 9/11 came
and the CIA literally in in the span of
a day
transformed from an organization
whose mission was to recruit spies to
steal secrets and then to analyze those
secrets to allow the policy makers the
best to make the best informed policy
to a paramilitary organization that had
created created a torture program, a
secret prison program, a rendition, an
extraordinary rendition program,
kill lists, assassination squads,
literally overnight and with an
unlimited budget to back it all up. And
that pendulum has not swung back yet. I
I'm not sure that it will. There there's
been this fundamental change within the
CIA.
So yeah, most of my career, twothirds of
my career was
was before 911.
You made me think of a off-the-wall
question, but it does make me wonder
because the state of the world at this
point or 2025 or we're dealing with
Russia, Ukraine,
if Russia had joined NATO, do you think
we'd be in the same mess we're in now?
>> No. And the Russians asked to join NATO
three separate times
under three presidents.
And three times we said, "Yeah, we we
don't think that's a very good idea."
But it actually was a good idea. The the
whole world would look differently
today.
Yeah. Correct me if I'm wrong because
I'm not deep into NATO, but I believe
the NATO rules are obviously if you
attack a NATO country, then all of NATO
attacks you. But that would include any
country within NATO attacking another
country. NATO turned on them. Correctly.
>> That's that's the big question because
Greece and Turkey Turkey are always at
odds. So what happens if Turkey attacks
Greece? And we've come, you know, within
hours a couple of times of Turkey
attacking Greece. Remember, like you say
in the charter, it's like section 40
says an attack on one is an attack on
all. The only time that has ever ever
been implemented was on 911
and so NATO had to come to the
assistance of the United States because
the United States had been attacked.
But yeah, then what would have happened
if if Russia is in NATO?
>> Well, and the reason why I'm asking is I
kind of feel like NATO was created as a
bull work against Warsaw Pact, you know,
like is
>> well well it was created first before
the Warsaw Pact. The Warsaw Pact was was
in response to NATO. And most of those
Warsaw packed countries didn't have
popular support. I mean, among their own
citizens.
>> It didn't matter because they were all
totalitarian, you know, communist
governments. Um, and that's why it fell
apart so quickly. That's why every
Warsaw packed country except Russia,
um, is a member of NATO today
>> and Ukraine.
>> Yeah. But it was part of the Soviet
Union. I mean, yeah.
>> Right. Oh, okay. Fair enough. Just
saying. But, um, okay. Well, I it was
just something I wanted to run by
because I just sort of feel like because
>> we never let them join or whatever, then
it was just kind of like a a permanent
belligerance because the whole point of
NATO was to go against what
>> Russia formerly was.
>> Mhm.
>> And imagine the trillions of dollars
that we've spent unnecessarily
uh in opposition to to the Russians.
money that could have been spent on our
own infrastructure, on medical care, on
education.
It's the the whole world would be a
different place.
Well, hopefully we can uh get to that at
some point. It's um kind of a
frustrating thing. Now, I wanted to ask
another question. I get weird, you know,
like I get sidetracked on different
things because I was, you know, looking
up. I saw New Yorker article on you and
it was saying that you retired from the
CIA in 2004 and I was like,
>> how's that possible?
>> I resigned.
>> Okay.
>> I don't know why so many journalists
have said that I retired in 2004. I
mean, I was 40 years old in 2004. I
didn't retire.
>> That That's what I thought to because
>> I don't know why they do that. They
always do that. Right. Well, and I I
went, you know, I was looking it up and
everything else. Well, but part of the
reason is because, you know, Pete
instructed me and he said, "I need to
talk to you about um pardons and
something that went down with you and I
read a little bit and obviously an
important factor of a pardon would be a
obviously being able to carry a weapon,
being able to vote, um but also being
able to collect a pension. And I'm
assuming that with your time with John
Kerry, your time with the CIA, you and
>> you you're collecting enough over the
government area to to get a a pensionw
worthy career. Can you tell me what went
down with um this whole pardon
situation?
>> Well, there are several iterations. So,
I had applied uh under the Obama
administration. I knew I wasn't going to
get it, but I have very, very strong
support within the Greek American
community. And there were three very
important Greek Americans, two
businessmen and an elected official. The
two businessmen, well, one's passed away
now, but are billionaires, were
billionaires, and very close to uh to
Joe Biden. So, I applied for the pardon
at their recommendation
and they said, "Let's go talk to Joe
Biden."
So, I had a package prepared. I have a
letter signed by 70 former CIA officers
asking Obama to pardon me. I had a
letter
written by the man who wrote the law
that I was convicted of violating saying
I should never have been charged with a
crime in the first place. that this was
not why he wrote the law. Um, a
statement from my congressman asking for
a pardon on the floor of the house and
an op-ed from the Christian Science
Monitor written by one senator Joseph R.
Biden saying this law was
unconstitutional and should never have
been passed.
So, I take the train to Wilmington. The
Greeks drive down from New York and we
meet with Biden and I give him the
package and I said, "Mr. Vice President,
if you could just weigh in with the
president." This is like 4 days before
the end of the Obama administration,
right? So, it's uh it's January of 2017
and he's like, "Well, you're so
controversial and I'm not sure and you
know the CIA hates you." And finally,
one of the Greeks says, "Joe, we've been
supporting you since 1972, and we've
never asked for anything. This is not
just for him. This is for the entire
Greek American community."
He says, "All right, I'll do it." I get
on the train. I go back home. They go to
the White House with Biden for dinner
that night. I'm a nervous wreck. I stay
up late. Finally, at midnight, they call
me and they said, "You would have been
so proud of Joe Biden tonight. He went
to the mat for you." But halfway through
his pitch, Obama put up his hands and
said, "Guys, I'm just not going to do
this. It's either him or it's Manning."
And Manning got 35 years.
And then that was it. So four days
later, Trump becomes president. I had
great support from the likes of of
Tucker Carlson, Steve Bannon, Brian
Kilme, all the usual people on on Fox
News because remember it was it was
Obama and Holder and Brennan that went
after me. Peter Stro at the FBI put the
cuffs on me. So all of their enemies are
the ones that targeted me. The ones that
targeted me targeted them later on.
And so I applied for a pardon under
Trump.
The last day of Trump's first term,
Tucker calls Tucker Carlson calls me and
he said, "You got to come on the show
again tonight. He's going to pardon Lil
Wayne." I said, "Little Wayne?"
This rapper,
he pardons Little Wayne. I said,
"Tucker, he's got to pardon me today.
It's the last day." As it turned out,
and I got this from a very reliable
source, he was going to pardon me and
Assange and Snowden.
But then Mitch McConnell called and
said, "If you pardon and Mitch McConnell
doesn't know me, but he said, "If you
pardon Snowden and Assange," he said, "I
will not be able to control Senate
Republicans, and they will vote to
convict you because remember, the
Democrats had impeached him on the House
side."
And so they dropped me. I went through
the whole pardon thing over again with
Biden, saying, "Remember me? You
supported a pardon four years ago, but
by then Biden was so demented
that I couldn't even really get to him
and they just passed me over. Now here I
am for the fourth time with the same
solid Republican support
and I don't know if it's going anywhere.
>> Wow. Um I was told that you might have
been named a price by representatives of
uh Rudy Giuliani.
>> I had a friend who was close to
Giuliani.
>> What happened?
>> And I I called him one day and I said I
said, "Can you get to Giuliani for me? I
want to ask for his help to get a
pardon. He said, "Yeah, I can I can set
up a a call."
So, he sets up a call. I talked to to
Giuliani's Major Domo and he says,
"Well, as it so happens, we're going to
be in Washington next week. Why don't we
meet up at the at the Trump Hotel?" I
said, "Great." I said, "I get off work
at 2. What do you say 2:30?" He said,
"No, Rudy's not really in good
functioning shape by 2:30. We're going
to have to do it earlier in the day.
I said, "Fine." I took the day off. We
met at noon. We we were sitting in in
the lounge area at the Trump Hotel. And
um it's Giuliani and two of his people
and my attorney and me. My attorney is a
serious guy. He used to be the deputy
attorney general under Reagan. So, we
sit there, shake hands with everybody.
Nice to meet you. And Giuliani says,
"Um,
hey, you follow uh you follow uh
football? How about the uh how about
those uh those Jets?"
I said, "Yeah, I follow football. I'm a
Steelers fan. I'm from Pittsburgh
originally near Pittsburgh. So, yeah, I
love the Steelers, but yeah, the Jets
are looking good this year."
Ah, he says, "I'm a baseball fan, too.
You like the Mets?" I said, "I like the
Pirates as bad as they are, but yeah, I
follow the Mets. We used to have a
really good rivalry." thinking, "What is
he talking about?" So, finally, I said,
"Mr. Mayor, there's this issue of a
pardon I wanted to talk to you about."
And he goes, "Anybody know where the
pisser is?" And he stands up and walks
away.
I said to his aid, "What just happened?"
And he said, "You never talked to Rudy
about a pardon. You talked to me about a
pardon." And I talked to Rudy. I said,
"All right, whatever." He says, "Rudy's
going to ask you for $2 million."
And I laughed. I said, ' 2 million? Why
in the world? I said, 'First of all, I
don't have $2 million. I'll never have
$2 million,
but secondly, why would I spend $2
million to recover a $700,000 pension?
Does that make any kind of sense? And I
said, look, I'm sorry to waste your
time, but that's what that's what we're
doing here. I looked at my attorney, he
looked at me, we stood up, we left.
That evening, I went to a book launch
event at the Republican National
Committee. A buddy of mine's a
Republican and he wrote this book and
whatever. So, I went up there and I ran
into another whistleblower, a friend of
mine who blew the whistle at TSA and he
very innocently said to me, "How was
your day today?" And I said, "Oh, listen
to this. I'll tell you how my day was."
So, I told him what I just told you. And
he says, "That's a felony." And I said,
"Oh, I know. I know." He's trying to
sell pardons and he said, "Did you call
the FBI?" I said, "The FBI doesn't give
a [__] about stuff like this." No, I
didn't call the FBI.
So, a couple of days pass and I get a
call from Mike Schmidt at the New York
Times. And I happened to be in my
lawyer's office when he called and
Schmidt says, "A little bird told me
that uh Rudy Giuliani tried to extort $2
million from you for a pardon." And I
said, "Oh, that Robert." He was so upset
when I told him. And Mike Schmidt says,
"Um, have you spoken to the FBI?" And I
said, "No, the FBI hasn't called me."
And he said, "Well, your friend called
the FBI and reported it as a crime." And
I said, "I haven't gotten any call from
the FBI." Mike says, "Would you be
willing to go on the record?" And I said
to my lawyer, "Am I willing to go on the
record?" And he said, "Go on the record.
You don't owe these people anything." So
I said, "Sure, I'll go on the record."
Well, it turns out Giuliani had asked
four or five different people who were
seeking pardons for $2 million each.
So, the article ran
front page above the fold on the
following Sunday.
I learned later from Giuliani's former
assistant, Noel Duny, that when the
story broke, Giuliani said that [__]
Kuryaku went public.
Well, Giuliani told the New York Times,
"I don't know who this man is. I never
met this man. He made the whole thing
up." So, Mike Schmidt called me back to
get a a comment, a response, and I said,
"He forgot that we took a picture
together.
before the meeting started.
So I emailed the picture to the New York
Times and it said Giuliani denied,
denied, denied, denied. The New York
Times has seen documentary proof that
the meeting took place.
So now Giuliani's broke and he's an
outcast and he's banned from Fox and
he's banned from Mara Lago and he owes a
billion dollars or whatever it is to
these women that he defamed and and Noel
Duny is suing him for sexual assault and
a whole bunch of other stuff. She she
never got paid all the time that that
she worked for him. Uh Giuliani's a
wreck. His life spun out of control. Um,
we know from his fourth divorce, from
from the the discovery that his ex-wife
leaked to the New York Times that he was
a member of 16 country clubs, that he
spent $10,000 a month on cigars and
brandy or whatever it was that he
scotch, whatever it was he was drinking.
And so he needed those $2 million
influxes to keep his lifestyle going.
And it just didn't happen for him.
>> So, just to be clear, it's very possible
that he was freelancing. Oh, I think I
think
>> not Trump at all.
>> Oh, no. No. I don't think it was Trump
at all. No, I think that he was telling
people that he could guarantee a pardon
because some of the money was going to
Trump. He didn't tell me that, but
that's what I've heard. But I don't
think Trump had any idea that this was
happening. I think Giuliani was just
trying to boogart the money.
>> Okay. Well, that's a very significant,
you know, point if Trump was involved or
not involved.
>> Yeah. No, no, not at all. Not at all.
Okay. Do you mind my asking what the
procedure is for somebody to get a
pardon? I mean, we always hear about
this and that. It's like, and you said I
put together a package and thing. Do you
mind breaking that down? I don't know if
you've ever done that before, but
>> I've never I have not I have not done
that, but it's a great question. It's an
important question because there's the
official way and then there's the
unofficial way. So the official way is
you go to the website of the US pardon
attorney and it gives you an option to
click to click on for a commutation of
sentence or a pardon. Now to apply for a
pardon you have to be 5 years past
the not just the end of your sentence
but the end of whatever paper you have
probation or parole or whatever it is 5
years after the fact. All right. And you
have to have shown remorse for whatever
crime you committed. And you have to
show that you're a a contributing
functioning member of society.
So then you can apply.
Before we go too far, and I'm sorry to
interrupt, but already little niggles
are coming off of my head. Um,
>> how would a preemptive pardon work on
that? And then how am pardon like Jimmy
Carter? That's the unofficial way.
>> Well, I was going to say because Jimmy
Carter also pardoned all the draft
dodgers. And uh by the way, I think that
that was within 5 years.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Of there committing a crime. So
>> that's right.
>> Oh, okay. So, please continue. I just
was pointing out a discrepancy.
>> The bottom line there is the president
can do anything he wants.
>> Anything at all. He has constitutional
authority to pardon anybody, anytime,
anywhere for any crime, federal crime.
So, the the official way is you go to
the website, you fill out the form, the
FBI does a background investigation,
says, "Yeah, this is all true." And then
the FBI
um meets with your prosecutor and with
your sentencing judge to get their
opinion. They always say no. No pardon.
>> Always. Just as a matter of of practice.
And then they make
>> So, you know what? They're like YouTube
when they uh when they demonetize a
video.
>> Yeah. Exactly.
>> Say, "I appeal." Denied.
>> Denied. That's it. And that's why, you
know, there are thousands of pardon
applications and commutation
applications every year and almost
nobody gets pardoned. Nobody who goes
through the actual process gets pardoned
because everybody always says, "No, no,
no, no." You know, danger to society,
whatever. Um,
the US pardon attorney then makes the
recommendation to the president. So, out
of these 3,000 applicants, we recommend
that these four, five people get
pardoned. and then the president makes
the final determination. That's the
official way. The unofficial way is you
fill out the form so you get a case
number, but then you hire a lobbyist or
you get yourself on the news all the
time or you have some advocate who's
close to the president or to the first
lady or you get some powerful senator
pick up the phone and call the president
or the president, you know, reads in the
paper, "Oh, this guy got screwed. I'm
going to pardon him." or he issues a
blanket pardon like Jimmy Carter did
with the the Vietnam War draft dodgers
or like Trump did with the January 6th
protesters. So So
>> or Biden did with the mass commutation
>> of marijuana um convictions.
>> Well, no death row. He mass commuted the
death row to
>> Yeah. Yeah. It was a mass commutation
except for
>> except for the Boston three the bos
Yeah. Zarnv and and the kid that that
went in and shot up the black church.
Okay.
>> South Carolina.
>> Yeah, South Carolina. Right.
>> I I forget his name.
>> So, it's a very messy, ugly, secretive
process. You never know where you stand.
You just never know.
>> So, you have to do it the right way just
so you can get that number. So,
>> you have to have the case number. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> You have to.
>> Yeah.
>> Prepare to be disappointed.
Well, I mean, being in the government,
the CIA, and working in the different
areas, you probably expected that to a
degree because
>> my time in the military and whatever
else, and you know, being around
government contractors, I'm used to
messy.
>> I'm used to nothing being a direct path
and the rules for the but not me and
that kind of thing.
>> Exactly. There's no fairness in this
whole process. Not at all. There never
has been. I mean, I shouldn't say there
never has been. There are stories about
Abraham Lincoln, for example, staying up
late at night by candle light and and uh
issuing pardons and commutations mostly
of of soldiers uh Union soldiers who had
gone awall because he he said that no
one should be executed for cowardice.
And so he would he would issue these
things, you know, even without
applications.
See, and this is another thing. The
office of the US pardon attorney when it
was established
in the in the 20th century was supposed
to be housed in the executive office of
the president at the old executive
office building. It was supposed to be a
a Chinese wall between DOJ and the US
pardon attorney. And it's not. it's
how's that DOJ and so you have all that
undue influence coming from from
prosecutors, US attorneys, you know,
people that have their own their own
positions on whether or not you deserve
a pardon. But I I'll add one other
thing. In my own case,
um
I applied when I when I got home from
prison, I applied to have my voting
rights reinstated in in Virginia. I live
in Virginia
and so I went online. It's the
governor's you go to the governor's
website and I filled out the form and I
sent it in and um I don't know 3, four
or five weeks passed and uh I hadn't
heard anything back. So I just called
the toll-free number and this guy
answered and he said uh well let me look
up your uh your application. And he
goes, "Oh, oh, okay. Uh yes,
uh it's being processed. uh just be
patient and we'll be in touch shortly.
It was kind of a funny response.
About a week later, two weeks later, my
doorbell rings at 7:00 in the morning
and I was already up and sitting at the
table having a cup of coffee.
So, I go to the door, I open the door,
and it's a courier and he has this big
envelope, like an 11 by14 envelope, and
it says office of the governor.
So, I open it up and it's this big
certificate with the the gold seal of
the state of V, the Commonwealth of
Virginia,
and it's a pardon from the governor. I
hadn't applied for a pardon.
>> Okay. So,
>> yeah.
>> Well, that doesn't work well in a
federal case, but
>> No, but it was a very generous It was a
very generous action
>> that the governor had taken, and I said,
"Are you kidding me? I pull it out. It's
like beautiful. Like
>> which governor, by the way?
>> Terry McCauliff.
>> McCauliff. Okay.
>> Yeah. So I was like, "Okay." So at 9:00
I I walked over to the courthouse
with my pardon. And um and I said, "I'd
like to register to vote." Oh, she says,
"Yeah, fill out this form." Well,
there's a little box and it says, "Have
you ever been convicted of a felony?"
And I said, "Yes." "Have you had your
voting rights reinstated?" I clicked
yes. or I checked. Yes. So, she pulls me
over to the side so nobody could hear
and she whispers to me, "I see that
you've checked the boxes. There's a man
who handles cases like yours, but he's
off today." I said, "Oh, no. This is the
last day to register to vote um because
the election is Tuesday."
And she said, "We'll take care of it.
You can vote on Tuesday." So, I get a
call from the guy Monday morning saying,
"I've approved your application to vote,
so come on in tomorrow and vote." Very
generous.
Um,
so I called the toll-free number again
and I said, "Listen, I I know I'm not
going to be able to get to the governor,
but I just wanted to say thank you for
this very generous uh act." I said, "The
governor doesn't know me." And he said,
"No, listen. I know your case." case. He
said the governor actually does know you
and he thought you were treated poorly
and so he just on his own valition
decided to issue you a pardon and he
says I know that doesn't really help but
he said it gives you back your right to
vote and it reinstates your state gun
rights and I said well you know from his
lips to God's ears I still don't have my
federal gun rights and he said I know
it's symbolic but he wanted to do it so
I sent a thank you note I'm sure he
never you saw it, but I sent a thank you
note saying, you know, I hope you run
for president because this is the most
generous thing anybody's ever done for
me.
>> And symbolically, I think it's still
important like you've resubmitted the
paperwork now, right? And I'm sure you
included that. Like, yes, look, even the
state governor saying, "Hey,
>> this guy got screwed." And you know,
I'll tell you what, when I was in
prison, it was six weeks before I was
released. I was allowed to call my wife
every other day for 15 minutes. And I
called her one day in December. This is
December of 2014. And I said, "How's
your day?" She said, "Great." I said,
"Really? Why was it great?" And she
said, "Because the Senate torture report
was released today and it proved that
everything you said was true." And John
McCain got up on the floor of the Senate
and said that John Kuryaku had provided
a great national service. he said
because without his revelations, the
American people would never have known
what the CIA was doing in their name.
And so I got out of prison and I was out
for like a week and I got a call from
McCain's office and the guy says,
"Senator McCain says, "Welcome home."
And he wants to know what he can do to
be helpful. I said, "Oh my god, thank
you. I need my pension back." They
confiscated my pension and I'm going to
have to work until the day I die if I
don't get it back. So what we did was we
met and my attorney and I met with
McCain's staff and and I'll add before
before my arrest when I was working for
Carrie, Carrie's office was right next
door to McCain's. So every time I'd run
into McCain, he would go out of his way
to come and shake my hand. How are you?
I'd say how are you senator? So good to
see you again. and always very generous,
shaking hands, patting me on the back.
Carrie even said to me one time, "Why
don't you and the cane get a room or
something?" And I said, "No, no, he's
he's serious. It's about the torture
thing." So, so my attorney, we decided
to do this absent a pardon cuz the Obama
people, we I knew the Obama people
weren't going to
>> Hold on. One of the Obama people was
Secretary of State Kerry.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> and he didn't stand up for you. I
emailed Carrie and I asked him for his
help to his personal email and he wrote
me back three days later, four days
later and he says, it was a very short
email. He said, "Please do not ever
attempt to contact me again."
That's John Kerry. So what we ended up
doing was we wrote we wrote a one
paragraph amendment to the National
Defense Authorization Act of 20
16.
And it said that every American
convicted of violating the Intelligence
Identities Pro uh Protection Act between
October 1st and October 31st of 2012
shall hereby have his pension
reinstated.
Okay. So, I'm the only American that
qualifies. And the idea was we're gonna
stick it in like page 1,535.
>> Yeah.
>> And then McCain got brain cancer
>> and he died and we couldn't get it into
the bill
and that was the end of it.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
So, you're still out there fighting.
Now, I think you told Pete that you had
three, it could have changed by now, but
um three of the FBI people or or an FBI
person and two other people. It may not
be FBI. I don't know what I heard.
>> Three FBI.
>> They were and they these were people who
actually worked your case who have
contacted you and said, "Hey, uh
>> yeah,
>> sorry, bro."
>> Mhm. three people, two called my lawyer
and then one emailed me directly and
said that he's actually lost sleep over
this over the years that the orders came
from the very top that at the working
level they didn't want to do this but
they had no choice and that he was sorry
that he played a role in what happened
to me.
>> It was it was generous but I mean
>> Yeah, but it's kind of like that.
>> It's kind of Yeah.
>> hollow in a way.
>> Yeah. Do you mind? And other than those
people, obviously they're going to want
to remain anonymous. Sure. Do you want
want to name names of people at the top
who have screwed you? You mentioned
Stro. I mean, that's a
>> Oh, I'm happy to name the names.
>> I mean, these guys are criminals.
Brennan, number one, Jose Rodriguez, the
former deputy director for operations at
the CIA. Uh, Eric Holder. In fact,
Trump's uh former US attorney in Utah,
Brett Tilman, said, and this is this was
his quote, "The Kuryaku case was the
template for Democratic part for the
Democratic Party's policy of Lafair."
The template. I was the first one that
they targeted to see, can we can we wrap
this guy up using Lawfair? And they did.
And when they saw that it worked against
me, they went after Trump.
>> Mhm. And not just Trump, these process
crimes, they went after Mike Flynn and
Steve Bannon and Paul Maniffort and all
different kinds of people.
>> Roger Stone.
>> Roger Stone raid his house at 6:00 in
the morning with very grave crime. No.
>> No.
>> Raided Mara Lago.
>> Yeah, they raided Mara Lago. Yeah. See,
but they never they never expected Trump
to to come out on top here.
>> And now they're beginning to panic. And
then you've got documentary evidence
that the likes of Clapper and Comey and
Brennan actually did commit crimes. The
only worry that I have is
on some of these crimes, we're bumping
up against the statute of limitations.
And so if charges are going to be filed,
they've got to be filed soon. There's a
there's a grand jury that's convened
currently in Washington. I kind of wish
that the grand jury had been convened in
the Eastern District of Virginia, the
espionage court, because they would be
far more likely to indict.
But I I hope they do the right thing and
wrap these guys up because look,
essentially what they were what what the
plan was was to effect a coup. They were
trying to deny Donald Trump the
presidency despite the fact that he had
legitimately defeated Hillary Clinton.
You know, to paint someone as a Russian
agent,
it's not just defamatory, it's dangerous
and they were trying to affect a coup.
I have something that I've been wanting
to do. A lot of people think I'm just
stupid for for wanting this. They're
like, "Oh, Justice Department, Justice
Department, that's all that matters.
I want there to be congressional
investigation."
>> Yeah. Real one.
>> And and and you know, like the church
committee and I mean,
>> exactly. Can Why can we not drag Clapper
and Brennan and and you talk about the
statute of limitations, but well,
contempt of Congress, that's fresh. If
uh if they perjure themselves, that's
fresh. And even if no ne never any
charge ever happens, putting some
sunlight on this would seem like a
possibly good idea. Totally agree. But
the problem is that there's a gigantic
difference between the church and pike
committees of 1975 and the Congress that
we have today. It is so much more
partisan. I mean, look at the the
special whatever it was called
weaponization whatever committee where
the only Republican
or Republicans were Swallwell and uh and
Cheney.
I mean, Republicans just wouldn't even
participate.
If if the decision were to be made to go
after Democrats, what Democrats would
participate?
We need Sam Irvin. We need Howard Baker.
We need Frank Church and and Otis Pike.
And these these giants, Daniel Patrick
Moyahan, these giants that served in the
1970s, they just don't exist anymore on
Capitol Hill.
>> Good point. If you watched the JFK
hearings, I don't know if you remember
that type of thing, but um
>> carrying the HCSA.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Compared to the late the drop this year,
right? forget almost. It's hilarious
because you have one side of the aisle
who's actually asking questions. Of
course, um getting Oliver Stone confused
with Roger Stone.
>> Oh my god, I saw that. Oh.
Oh my god.
>> It's like, oh, that's not the best
choice in the world. But anyway, um
comparing that to the um HCSA where I
mean it was packed house. This is like
an empty conference room. They they
don't even stage it to make it look like
it's a little bit more crowded. It just
looks, you know, like all the congress
people are sitting way back in their
seats. There's all this space. It just
>> it feels really like amateur hour and
they and a lot of the questions being
asked I think are not
>> the best I've ever heard.
>> Yeah. We just don't have intellectual
giants on Capitol Hill like we used to.
intellectual giants who who who
weren't afraid to lead, you know, they
would lead and then bring their
constituents along with them. Now it's
the reverse. They just pander to to to
the extremes of their constituencies.
>> All right. Well, I want to go the other
direction now because
everything has been kind of dark that
we've been talking about and
all these bad operators, bad characters
that are, you know, saturating the
government and it is really hard for me
because like I'll interview different
people um you know, like some FBI agents
who are pretty good people. I mean,
they're they're busy. They're, you know,
busting up bank robbers that, you know,
they're they're doing real work and
everybody's gotten so cynical because
the James Comeies of the world and all
of that.
Maybe you can help me by pointing out
who are some heroes.
Well, I'll say Tucker Carlson's a hero
of mine.
um he was liberated
when he was pushed out of Fox News and
he's able to
go deep on issues that he feels strongly
about. And I find myself agreeing I
listen I I consider myself a lifelong
leftist but I also believe that the
ideological spectrum is not a straight
line from the left to the right. It's a
circle. It's a circle. Yeah. Or I I
think it's a circle because it meets at
one point.
>> Well, I was thinking of it like a U,
like a magnet, and that the magnet
points attract all the psychos.
>> I used to I used to believe that, but I
don't anymore.
>> I don't anymore. No, because I find
myself strongly agreeing with people on
the right on issues of civil liberties.
Strongly. And government overreach. I
don't want NSA collecting my data.
It's not just illegal. It's a part of
NSA's charter that they may not collect
on US persons. That's American citizens
or anybody in the country in a green
card. And that's practically all they
do.
>> Well, that's a libertarianist view, too.
>> Yeah. Well, the libertarian is
traditionally
view because that's kind of the bottom.
So I I I think of it as um I guess I'm
at the compass where you have a
authoritarian top, libertarian bottom
and it's kind of like a you like
everything goes to authoritarian
over time and that's why I was saying
the magnet with a freak. So I I just
wanted to clarify
because all these things when you design
them it's helpful to have a good point.
But yeah, I think that there's been a
flip on that.
>> I think Tucker is somebody we should
take very seriously, very seriously. and
he's talking about issues that that most
in the mainstream just don't even want
to approach.
But he's getting the truth out there.
You know, he's not afraid of them.
A lot of other people are. Most people
in the mainstream are. So I I like and
trust Tucker very very much. And I find
myself agreeing with other people. What
about in the government though? I meant,
you know, like it's like is every FBI
agent you've come across bad or every
CIA or were there, you know, that's I
was kind of um going on that there's got
to be some good operators.
>> Yeah, I can't mention their names.
>> Oh, yeah. No, no, I can't do that. But
yes, there there are there are good
people out there. In fact, the vast
majority of people at the CIA are very
bright, very patriotic people who want
nothing more than to serve the country.
But leadership, you know, where the
decisions are made about who lives and
who dies with no real oversight. There's
there's literally nobody on the House or
Senate intelligence oversight committees
that I have any respect for at all.
Nothing. Because they don't oversee.
They just nod and say, "Okay, do
anything you want."
>> Wow. Interesting. Interesting. Well, I
kind of figured that
from what I've seen, you um started at
the left or you were kind of left or
whatever, which
>> and I agree with you. I think that a lot
of those labels are outdated and
>> um you know, there's the whole quote
southern strategy,
>> right?
>> Uh where this flipped, that flipped,
it's um
people who believe in the constitution
or they don't believe in the
constitution. There's a corporatist
versus non-corporatist. I I'm I don't
know. Maybe you see eye to eye with
populism to a point.
>> I do.
>> I don't.
>> To a point.
>> Yeah. That's kind of I think I think
that's where things line up because a
lot a lot of this I think is really
Trump.
>> Trump brought a lot out in my opinion.
>> Yes.
>> With MAGA and and by then I'm not just
saying no Trump is a cult or this and
that. I mean a lot of people who are
supposed Bernie bros, right, went to
Trump.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Because of the
populism.
Yeah, you know, I disagree with MAGA
populists on some issues. I think I
think healthcare is a human right.
Everybody should have healthcare and it
should be as close to free as possible,
right? That should be from the taxes
that we pay. We pay astronomical taxes.
So rather than spend a trillion dollars
on DoD, a lot of that money should go to
healthcare. At the same time, Trump is
right about the border. We we just can't
just, you know, let everybody in and and
say, "Well, we'll we'll deal with the
fallout later." No, there are processes.
Now, right before the 911 attacks,
George W. Bush had negotiated a deal
with the Mexicans where we would
legalize many of the workers here and
give them 9month work visas. So they
would cross the border legally, they
would work there nine months, they would
pay federal and state taxes, and then go
back to Mexico, have the visa renewed,
and then repeat the same thing that the
next year. That agreement was never
implemented because 9/11 just threw a
wrench into everything. But it was a
great idea.
>> Well, we kind of have that now. I've
been in arguments. No, I No, I've been
in arguments with people like if you go
to Disney World,
>> that's different.
>> I I understand it's different program,
but I'm using as a template. Yeah. You
see, you know, badges from all around
the world and these are legal employees
and there are some degree of taxes paid.
>> I think that that agreement a lot of
people probably spiked it in the back
end because the business owners often
don't want to pay the federal taxes on
the employee. It's cheaper to pay under
the table essentially cash on the side.
That's right.
>> And I think that,
>> you know, Mitt Romney, I'm not a big fan
of, but I do agree with the idea of if
you track it and you track the employer,
you say, "Hey,
>> um, if you hire somebody and we catch
you, you're going to pay a penalty of
like 25,000, 50,000, you know, a heavy
enough penalty to where it's no longer
cost effective. At the same time, maybe
reduce the federal taxes on those visas,
you know, so there could be kind of a
little bit of a balance to where you're
like, okay, we understand you want to
pay as much taxes on them, but let's go
somewhere in the middle. And I think
something like that could work. Maybe
Trump could do it. I don't know. I I I'm
not sure. But that's a conversation.
Trump's a dealmaker and so maybe maybe
he can do it.
>> It would be an interesting legacy.
Definitely. Now, uh we're about out of
time. I always like to ask one last
question with you. It's like God only
knows what I'm going to get. Um because
it's you have such a buried career. And
what I always like to ask is what is the
one question I should have asked you and
I neglected to.
>> Wow. That's that's a tough one, man.
>> I have an alternative. Well, you know,
the the one question that people do ask
me that I still cannot answer
>> is how do we affect change and how do we
solve some of these problems? And I I
always give a lame response that, you
know, we've got to take to the streets
and we've got to write and we have to
speak and we have to lobby and but we do
all that
>> and things just seem to get worse and
more partisan.
Have you ever heard of Daryl Davis?
>> Sure.
>> It's a hero of mine.
>> Maybe he has the answer.
>> I hope
>> he talks to people.
>> Just talks to people
>> one-on-one. Yep.
>> And goes to where they are.
>> Mhm.
>> And just keeps talking. And because
he sets up a scenario where they hate
all black people,
>> but there's a problem. They like Daryl.
>> Yeah.
>> So they hate all black people except for
Daryl.
>> Except for Daryl. Now it breaks down
>> the paradigm, right,
>> of
that. So I'm wondering if instead of
marching and yelling and screaming,
>> maybe everybody should have a coffee.
>> See, that's a that's a lovely idea.
Actually, I met Daryl in
Berlin
over coffee.
>> Oh, wow. Yeah, we were both speakers at
an event in Berlin back in like 2020,
maybe 2021. It was co I remember. Um,
and I was like, "Wow, this guy makes a
lot of sense."
Yeah, good guy.
Yeah, he's kind of a hero of mine. Been
trying to get him on forever, but we'll
see if it'll ever happen.
>> Good luck,
>> John. Thank you so much. This has been
really great. My pleasure. appreciate
the information about things that I'd
never know about.
>> Oh, thank you. Thanks for having me.
Good to see you.